[{"id": "5fde4f1fc6c6b019850c9a88", "question": "Who, according to the Bible, led the Israelites into The Promised Land?", "answer": "Joshua", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11c", "question": "Which Greek island was the center of the Minoan civilization?", "answer": "Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ce7", "question": "What Nobel Prize-winning author committed suicide by gunshot in 1961?", "answer": "Ernest Hemingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c4bf877e98cb977789a5", "question": "How many US states share a border with Quebec?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ddc", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"dungarees\"?", "answer": "Hindi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d6", "question": "How many yards are there in a mile?", "answer": "1760", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f11", "question": "Who starred as the Doctor in the TV show \"Dr. Who\" from 1963 to 1966?", "answer": "William Hartnell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b338", "question": "When was Buckingham Palace built?", "answer": "1703", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b88d", "question": "In which city would you find Wembley stadium?", "answer": "London", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1c27baab681b0929219f", "question": "What car did Chevrolet design the Camaro to compete with in 1966?", "answer": "The Ford Mustang", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0c7", "question": "Who was also known as \"The Scourge of God\"?", "answer": "Attila the Hun", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dea", "question": "What was the name of Jimmy Nelson's dummy?", "answer": "Farfel the Dog", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b287", "question": "Molotov cocktails were first used by what country after the Soviets invaded it in 1939?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5eb7382c5e259d786908732d", "question": "What book by George Orwell had a film adaption that was funded by the CIA?", "answer": "Animal Farm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "597cde1fe347d002c297e4f9", "question": "Who wrote the classic science fiction trilogy \"Helliconia\"?", "answer": "Brian W. Aldiss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d05b41a1c922dd1ac64a4", "question": "Who wrote the song \"Moon River\" performed by Audrey Hepburn in the film \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Henry Mancini", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ca3d1c44f0f6af5b066637", "question": "Who had a hit in 1996 with the song \"Wannabe\"?", "answer": "Spice Girls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eab", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Jughaid and Tater?", "answer": "Barney Google and Snuffy Smith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b427", "question": "With which war is Florence Nightingale associated?", "answer": "Crimean\u00a0", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a09c", "question": "Whose normal heartbeat is 242 per minute?", "answer": "Spock's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dcf", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"chutzpah\"?", "answer": "Yiddish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393d7", "question": "Which song became synonymous with \"The Bridge on the River Kwai\"?", "answer": "The Colonel Bogey March", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a872", "question": "What is the name of the mainland portion of the province originally called Newfoundland?", "answer": "Labrador", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b375", "question": "Who was the first female American in space?", "answer": "Sally Ride", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590721963745b36be73039f8", "question": "What were Frosty the Snowman\u2019s eyes made out of?", "answer": "Coal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5967605b2b59efe0e9417e9c", "question": "What band earned their first #1 hit song with \"Boondocks\"?", "answer": "Little Big Town", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b391", "question": "Who won the first Boat Race between Oxford and Cambridge?\u00a0", "answer": "Oxford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff25a5031a458464a93c470", "question": "Who was the headline performer featured at the conclusion of the opening ceremony of the 2012 Summer Olympics in London?", "answer": "Paul McCartney", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08d", "question": "The British passed the Intolerable Acts as punishment for what act by the American colonists?", "answer": "The Boston Tea Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571c9167df192a942e3376", "question": "What is Pele's birth name?", "answer": "Edson Arantes do Nascimento", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959a", "question": "What city is besieged by dragons in the 2002 movie \"Reign of Fire\"?", "answer": "London", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f721aa9e54d890926f6ea", "question": "In which ocean can you find Australia\u2019s Great Barrier Reef?", "answer": "Pacific -- It is comprised of over 3,000 reef systems and contains over 400 different types of coral and is visible from space.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600243324be4723ccac22192", "question": "Which George Eliot novel is set in a fictitious Midlands town in the UK between 1829 and 1832?", "answer": "\"Middlemarch\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2cf8c2596a59cbdfbd370", "question": "Who said, \u201cThe secret of happiness, you see, is not found in seeking more, but in developing the capacity to enjoy less\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339398", "question": "Who directed the movie \"The Pianist\"?", "answer": "Roman Polanski", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3232dabf195a31e15d7394", "question": "What year was Jodie Foster's directorial debut film, \"Little Man Tate\", released?", "answer": "1991", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b358a735db0d66a186cb553", "question": "What is the birth name of actress Paula Prentiss?", "answer": "Paula Ragusa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5906837bff9c0647b50a80a7", "question": "Which electronic duo did The Weeknd collaborate with for his song, \"Starboy\"?", "answer": "Daft Punk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938f", "question": "What role did James Dean play in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "Jim Stark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc19", "question": "What company introduced Spam to the market in 1937?", "answer": "Hormel Foods Corporation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963f", "question": "In which country was Greta Garbo born?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d66", "question": "Who played the role of TV's D. J. Tanner?", "answer": "Candace Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab43", "question": "Vienna is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c89d41011619dd6d415484", "question": "What book did Butters write as a sequel to \"Scrotie McBoogerballs\"?", "answer": "The Poop That Took a Pee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e5", "question": "What two neighboring beaches in Rio de Janeiro each inspired hit songs?", "answer": "Copacabana and Ipanema", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd16", "question": "What term is used for surfers and skaters who prefer to have their left foot on the back of the board?", "answer": "Goofy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a863", "question": "The popular tourist destination, Amalfi, is located in which province in the Italian Campania region?", "answer": "Salerno", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfc", "question": "The shoe company Converse is owned by what major corporation?", "answer": "Nike", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c0", "question": "What Western star rode a horse named Buttermilk?", "answer": "Dale Evans", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f22801dd7bf43be5e80d", "question": "What do skydivers traditionally do for their 100th jump?", "answer": "They skydive nude", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c82c", "question": "Thomas Edison was \"the Wizard of Menlo Park\" in what US state?", "answer": "New Jersey", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133babb", "question": "What was the combined points scored in Super Bowl II?", "answer": "47", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b556", "question": "What is Hershey's most popular product?", "answer": "Reeses Peanut Butter Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e29", "question": "Who is Carrie Fisher's mother?", "answer": "Debbie Reynolds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c991", "question": "What is the young of a pigeon called?", "answer": "Squab", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9a", "question": "In the children?s nursery rhyme, what comes next after ?Mary, Mary quite contrary??", "answer": "How does your garden grow?", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3b", "question": "What is actor Anthony Hopkins nationality by birth?", "answer": "Welsh", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b766", "question": "The phrase \"sticky wickeet\" has its origins in what sport?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3d", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"In the Drain\"?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ada8", "question": "Who was the first Boy Scout to become a US president?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf82", "question": "What country celebrates its National Day on 14th July?", "answer": "France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ec7231757c9fcac0ce7197a", "question": "What horse broke a Triple Crown drought lasting over 30 years?", "answer": "American Pharoah", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a0", "question": "How many years did it take to construct the Tower of Pisa?", "answer": "199", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea48b7ff048f679a45abb2", "question": "What natural biological defense system protects the body from disease and fights off germs?", "answer": "Immunity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af82", "question": "Who died three months into his 4th term as president?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8b", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Aliaune Thiam?", "answer": "Akon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071c5e3745b36be73039cb", "question": "What is the name of Tony Chu\u2019s daughter in the \"Chew\" comics series?", "answer": "Olive Chu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d9", "question": "What movie starred Sean Penn playing the role of gay rights activist Harvey Milk?", "answer": "Milk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b85ae662d71a53651022", "question": "Petroglyph is an engraving or image created on what?", "answer": "Stone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7cc", "question": "What bird is Britain's VTOL \"jump jet\" named for?", "answer": "The Harrier hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea1", "question": "Which was the oldest Marx brother?", "answer": "Chico", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed2", "question": "What is the flower that stands for \"a heart ignorant of love\"?", "answer": "White rosebud", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ca0", "question": "What 1980s TV shows featured sisters Missy and Tracey Gold, respectively?", "answer": "\"Benson\" and \"Growing Pains\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc90", "question": "Who is the only founding member of both the International Surfing and Swimming Halls of Fame?", "answer": "Duke Kahanamoku", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf42", "question": "Who invented the Polaroid camera?", "answer": "Edwin Land", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacc", "question": "Who perfected the first American revolver?", "answer": "Samuel Colt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87a", "question": "The first atomic bomb test split an atom of what fissionable element?", "answer": "Plutonium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59008a56cf842fa4c4ba968f", "question": "What nationality was Johnny Weissmuller?", "answer": "Hungarian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f6f7fe83fe1f2a824c1f", "question": "After Jesus fasted in the desert, what was His first temptation in the wilderness?", "answer": "Turn stone into bread", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c3082b316f4693fb67a5", "question": "In 2004, NYC took legal action against vendors at an Ecuadorian festival to prevent them from selling the meat of which animal?", "answer": "Guinea Pigs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfe", "question": "What year were the Ray-Ban Wayfarer sunglasses introduced to the market?", "answer": "1956", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea4447ff048f679a45ab8c", "question": "What is the anti-matter equivalent of an electron?", "answer": "Positron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338958", "question": "What 1974 novel explores the metaphysics of quality during a 17-day motorcycle journey across the US?", "answer": "Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d07341a1c922dd1ac64b6", "question": "Who was first to voice Porky Pig from 1935 to 1937?", "answer": "Joe Dougherty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa52", "question": "What is the capital of Mauritania?", "answer": "Nouakchott", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a799", "question": "Opened in 1928, the original Gorky Park is an amusement park located in what world capital city?", "answer": "Moscow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ae", "question": "What year did J. D. Salinger publish the novel \"The Catcher in the Rye\"?", "answer": "1951", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d077f4870e6f05ba600869", "question": "What role did Matthew McConaughey play in the 1995 film \"Boys on the Side\"?", "answer": "Abe Lincoln", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb47c65ff7d326b622a89", "question": "What is Nelophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Glass", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ab1b2aa4fda37788a9a1dbc", "question": "Scotophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928f", "question": "What object lands in Donnie Darko's bedroom?", "answer": "A jet engine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba53", "question": "What stadium was nicknamed \"The House That Ruth Built\"?", "answer": "Yankee Stadium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c2", "question": "Which of Hitler's deputies flew to Scotland in 1941 to try and negotiate peace with the UK?\u00a0", "answer": "Rudolf Hess", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cefc114948005ec986edce3", "question": "Who is the tenth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Chuu", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2cd", "question": "What is the square root of one-quarter?", "answer": "one-half", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbac", "question": "What sport takes place in a velodrome?", "answer": "Track cycling", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b885364247bf200fb881", "question": "The Easter lily is a native plant of which country?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a1", "question": "Which literary bear got its name from a London railway station?", "answer": "Paddington Bear", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab71", "question": "Which ocean does Bangladesh have direct access to?", "answer": "Indian Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa8a573838c5c8a417f3f", "question": "How are elements organized on the periodic table?", "answer": "By atomic number - The atomic number corresponds to the number of protons in the nucleus.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad97", "question": "Who succeeded Spiro Agnew as vice president of the United States?", "answer": "Gerald Ford", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad37", "question": "Who was the 42nd President of the United States?", "answer": "Bill Clinton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fc", "question": "What 1992 film features the characters Colonel Nathan Jessup and Lieutenant Daniel Kaffee?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000f0cd9a72b906b34e3cfd", "question": "Gala, honeycrisp and jazz are all varieties of which fruit?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ee33fe83fe1f2a824c07", "question": "David Jung is considered by many to be the originator of which famous food?", "answer": "Fortune cookies", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60136faa1381754895396379", "question": "In 2000, what character was elected U.S. President in the DC universe?", "answer": "Lex Luthor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e4b4fe83fe1f2a824bb6", "question": "At what conference did the Allies set the terms for the Japanese surrender?", "answer": "The Potsdam Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f1", "question": "Who played the role of Batman in the 1995 film \"Batman Forever\"?", "answer": "Val Kilmer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4ae449076251badbeabd", "question": "Who earned the nickname \"Moses\" in the Underground Railroad?", "answer": "Harriet Tubman -- One of the most well-known coordinators of the Underground Railroad, she helped more than 70 slaves to freedom.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a97820565ad31a57c804", "question": "Where is the \"grassy knoll\" located?", "answer": "Dealey Plaza, Dallas, Texas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c52f", "question": "What is the nearest star to Earth?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b455", "question": "What year was the Gettysburg Address delivered?", "answer": "1863", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c8d4fbde8045e48466e1", "question": "Why do some plants send chemical signals to bugs?", "answer": "Signal for help -- Leafy tobacco plants send a chemical signal to wasps, who will seek out caterpillars eating the leaves.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59e8071fde59ea584496feb7", "question": "Who invented the aerosol spray can?", "answer": "Erik Rotheim", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f74", "question": "Who was the first novelist to present a typed manuscript to his publisher?", "answer": "Mark Twain", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b0", "question": "If you were infected with the variola virus, what disease did you have?", "answer": "Smallpox", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cff", "question": "What category of writing are the Hugo Awards given for?", "answer": "Science-fiction", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecc23eec223966ae8f8873", "question": "Razzie awards are meant to go to bad movies, but who got nominated for directing the now widely respected film Scarface?", "answer": "Brian De Palma", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339361", "question": "What occupation did Mary Richards have on \"The Mary Tyler Moore Show\"?", "answer": "Assistant producer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdfbfec003d27d341092bda", "question": "What is the largest lake in Alaska?", "answer": "Iliamna Lake", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6018bd93d96d05b23b28165d", "question": "What were the earliest forms of contraceptive made from?", "answer": "Crocodile dung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600244634be4723ccac221a2", "question": "What is the movement in architecture in which buildings have an organic, amoeba-shaped form?", "answer": "Blobism\u00a0or\u00a0blobitecture\u00a0is a type of wavy, curvy building design without traditional edges or traditional symmetric form.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87f", "question": "What four letters are directly to the right of \"Q\" on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "W, E, R, T", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af16", "question": "Why were Julius and Ethel Rosenberg executed in 1953?", "answer": "Espionage", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cb", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Aliens\"?", "answer": "James Cameron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f0c06682715b82711cd9", "question": "What does the RIP stand for in Latin?", "answer": "Requiescat in pace", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a990761d1b4d384d5d695", "question": "What year was the radio show \"Gunsmoke\" adapted for TV?", "answer": "1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c6f1877e98cb977789c5", "question": "Which East Asian country celebrates Golden Week?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358d245db0d66a186cb55f", "question": "Who or what was Rosanna Arquette desperately seeking in 1985?", "answer": "Susan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133992f", "question": "What was Van Halen\u2019s first, and only #1 hit on the US Billboard singles chart?", "answer": "Jump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c596", "question": "Blacked eyed peas are not peas, what are they?", "answer": "Beans", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339036", "question": "For what occassion did George Frideric Handel compose the anthem \"Zadok the Priest\"?", "answer": "Coronation of King George II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339305", "question": "In the movie \"Gremlins\", what is the name of the little Mogwai given to Billy?", "answer": "Gizmo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d185873b17032616b59100", "question": "When was Nescafe's instant coffee first launched?", "answer": "1938", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d74", "question": "Gene Siskel owned the iconic white suit from what movie?", "answer": "Saturday Night Fever", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e97cfebfabb9c85d8a966", "question": "What TV show has the character Michael Stivic?", "answer": "All in the Family", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59bb2966c9bff04efae6d756", "question": "Who wrote the music for \"Joseph and the Amazing Technicolor Dreamcoat\"?", "answer": "Andrew Lloyd Webber", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e9", "question": "What was the first animated feature nominated for a best picture Oscar?", "answer": "Beauty and the Beast", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e93747ccba3ffe45786c6", "question": "Who invented the \"Miner's Lamp\"?", "answer": "Humphry Davy", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe9f5efff048f679a45aad9", "question": "What physicist discovered that a wave's frequency changes when the source and the observer are in motion relative to one another?", "answer": "Christian Doppler", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1b2", "question": "What boxer was nicknamed the Boston Strong Boy?", "answer": "John L. Sullivan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a628", "question": "Which US state is home to Hot Springs National Park?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b08f", "question": "What city hosted the 2010 Winter Olympics?", "answer": "Vancouver", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339048", "question": "Which Tennesee Williams play is about a Italian-American woman?", "answer": "The Rose Tattoo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133891d", "question": "Who created Iron Man?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b541", "question": "What does Seoul, the South Korean capital mean in the Korean language?", "answer": "The Capital", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b036", "question": "In what year did Pac-\u00adMan make its US debut?", "answer": "1980", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc42", "question": "What country was tennis player Novak Djokovic born in?", "answer": "Yugoslavia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989ac3acb8751d53e7d7609", "question": "In the gaming world, what does Mt. Gox stand for?", "answer": "Magic: The Gathering Online Exchange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66d94a5bfecdd737e08a3", "question": "What was the most popular month for weddings in the U.S. in 2019?", "answer": "October", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf84", "question": "What is British politician William Hague's middle name?", "answer": "Jefferson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5b", "question": "What Broadway great's daughter wrote the book \"Freaky Friday\"?", "answer": "Richard Rodgers'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d14", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Spawning\"?", "answer": "Piranha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff6", "question": "What is Johnny Chase's nickname on the TV show \"Entourage\"?", "answer": "Drama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65869ae7e414034b5aeef", "question": "Who was the leading ace for Norway in WWII?", "answer": "Svein Heglund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc74", "question": "What was the name of Henry Ford's only son?", "answer": "Edsel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b794", "question": "In skiing, what is a mogul?", "answer": "A bump or small hill", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339338", "question": "What US state is Sheldon from the TV show \"The Big Bang Theory\" from?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca61", "question": "What name is given to the diagram in which sets are represented by circles?", "answer": "Venn Diagram\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339df5", "question": "What red wine does Paul Giamatti refuse to drink in the movie \"Sideways\"?", "answer": "Merlot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d45", "question": "What folk hero is said to have been born in Loxley, South Yorkshire?", "answer": "Robin Hood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe69d9920565ad31a57c778", "question": "Which national reserve ended in 2015 after the Supreme Court declared it was unconstitutional?", "answer": "National Raisin reserve", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4b", "question": "What is Ralph Lauren's real last name?", "answer": "Lifschitz", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b624", "question": "What sign of the zodiac is represented by a bull?", "answer": "Taurus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e804aade59ea584496fea6", "question": "In which sport must the ball have a diameter of at least 42.67 millimetres and weigh no less than 45.93 grams?", "answer": "Golf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b537", "question": "How many dots are there on a pair of dice?", "answer": "Forty-two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e39", "question": "According to Fountains of Wayne, whose mom \"has got it goin' on\"?", "answer": "Stacy's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea39f9ff048f679a45ab29", "question": "What element is named after the Greek word for green?", "answer": "Chlorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b68", "question": "What Shakespearean play begins with the line \"Who's there\"?", "answer": "Hamlet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca89", "question": "What element that is lacking in a diet causes goitre?", "answer": "Iodine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff2", "question": "Who sang lead vocals for the rock band Hole?", "answer": "Courtney Love", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baad", "question": "Taekwondo was developed in what country?", "answer": "Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b323343bf195a31e15d739a", "question": "Gaborone is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Botswana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600784b0bd51d85e222ab65d", "question": "Who said, \"Champagne should be dry, cold, and free\".?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c867", "question": "What is the heaviest chemical element on the periodic table?", "answer": "Uranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f90", "question": "Which character is the narrator of Melville's \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a6f720565ad31a57c7e3", "question": "What is considered the turning point of World War II in Europe?", "answer": "Battle of Stalingrad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa51", "question": "What US city is known as \"The Insurance Capital of the World\"?", "answer": "Hartford, Connecticut", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5cefc077948005ec986edcdb", "question": "Who is the second member of the group LOONA to debut? ", "answer": "Hyunjin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b323135bf195a31e15d7382", "question": "What were the names of the host and his sidekick on the TV show \"Fantasy Island\"?", "answer": "Mr. Roarke and Tattoo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339568", "question": "Who play the burglars in, Home Alone?", "answer": "Joe Pesci and Daniel Stern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c1", "question": "Which South American country shares its name with a nut?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f1", "question": "Shortbread originated in what country?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338899", "question": "Who were the Three Musketeers?", "answer": "Arthos, Porthos, Aramis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b1", "question": "In what non-Spanish-speaking city would you find the Spanish Steps?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdf1", "question": "What rare economic condition results when rising prices and recession occur at once?", "answer": "Stagflation", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339449", "question": "How much are the guns worth in the 1998 movie \"Lock, Stock and Two Smoking Barrels\"?", "answer": "$250,000", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f51501dd7bf43be5e827", "question": "Which type of triangle has no equal sides?", "answer": "Scalene", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5bfdffddb668d7dfe168b5bc", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a812", "question": "Which South American country borders both the Caribbean Sea and the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339127", "question": "What French composer wrote the opera \"Samson and Delilah\"?", "answer": "Camille Saint-Saens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ee", "question": "What organization in the Harry Potter series is named after Dumbledore's patronus?", "answer": "Order of the Phoenix", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c8", "question": "Which car maker made the EV-1 vehicle?", "answer": "GM", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdab48c0b8cce1e6fda7048", "question": "What is the main ingredient in falafel?", "answer": "Chickpeas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff51487ff04d658268c92e3", "question": "What Spartan king led a small army of 300 Spartans against a vastly superior Persian force in the Battle of Thermopylae?", "answer": "Leonidas, King of Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b3711b1c3f17ccc40c8e1c", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60078b970eee65b76b9f266a", "question": "The Ptolemy dynasty ruled which ancient kingdom?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ab1be6baab681b0929219c", "question": "What year did Porsche introduce the 911?", "answer": "1963", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a62f", "question": "What is the two letter postal abbreviation for Massachusetts?", "answer": "MA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8b03401dd7bf43be5e78c", "question": "What was the Easter Bunny's original name?", "answer": "Osterhase", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00a", "question": "What was \"Ponch\"s real first name on CHiPs?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf0f", "question": "Where does the famous \"running of the bulls\" take place?", "answer": "Pamplona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a87", "question": "What author wrote \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\" short story?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b3c501dd7bf43be5e7b4", "question": "What TV show inspired the term \"spam\" for junk email?", "answer": "\"Monty Python's Flying Circus\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c774", "question": "What animal species name is slang for the mechanics profession?", "answer": "Monkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc0", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Paula Abdul?", "answer": "Rush Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59db788c0ab2c8f322317ff4", "question": "What is the capital of Panama?", "answer": "Panama City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae9e", "question": "What did the 1944 education act raise the school leaving age to in the UK?", "answer": "15", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b75", "question": "In \"Napoleon Dynamite\", what type of animal is Napoleon's grandmother's pet, Tina?", "answer": "llama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339100", "question": "What color was Rudolph the Reindeer's nose?", "answer": "Red", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ab3", "question": "\"Little Bastard\" was the nickname given to the Porsche 550 Spyder that killed what acting icon in a crash?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370831381754895396382", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", the fictitious film that Kevin watches, \"Angels with Filthy Souls\", is a homage to what real film?", "answer": "\"Angels with Dirty Faces\" -- It is a 1938 gangster film starring James Cagney and Pat O'Brien.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ebb408d98002fdd633b1", "question": "When was the maiden voyage of the \"Titanic\"?", "answer": "1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5971de3089261e916c8e09a1", "question": "In the US, a pint of milk is equal to how many cups of milk?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f75", "question": "What school does Harry Potter attend?", "answer": "Hogwarts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008c0acf842fa4c4ba969c", "question": "Mysophobia is the irrational fear of what?", "answer": "Contamination", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b735", "question": "What brand of gasoline introduced an additive called \"Platformate\" in 1968?", "answer": "Shell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a21", "question": "What color spot led tot he death of Billy Bones in \"Treasure Island\"?", "answer": "Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec877fec223966ae8f8815", "question": "Which rock legend's real name is William Bailey?", "answer": "Axl Rose", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338908", "question": "How many spikes are there on the The Statue of Liberty's crown?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdcc", "question": "What is Gary Gygax's claim to fame?", "answer": "Co-creator of Dungeons & Dragons", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a730", "question": "What desert is home to the Saguaro Cacti?", "answer": "Sonoran Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133957e", "question": "What game was played for money by the Vietnamese in \"The Deer Hunter\" movie?", "answer": "Russian Roulette", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391dd", "question": "Who played Mr. Orange in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Tim Roth", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4eed806d333868d34d776", "question": "Where did the croissant originate?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19d", "question": "What former country was tennis player Martina Hingis born in?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feb58617e83c707845b20ce", "question": "The Haymarket Affair, which is widely considered to be the event which led to May Day becoming the international event known as International Workers Day, occurred in which country?", "answer": "USA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b153", "question": "On Christmas Day 800 A.D., who was coronated as emperor of the Holy Roman Empire?", "answer": "Charlemagne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b466e662d71a53650fe9", "question": "Sandro Botticelli's \"Primavera\" features which Roman deity?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb56", "question": "What brand of whisky was created in 1939 Queen of England's visit to Canada?", "answer": "Crown Royal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef96266ce05a3942286e9b", "question": "What was Meryl Streep's birth name?", "answer": "Mary Louise", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b129", "question": "What was known as the Lady of the Lamp?", "answer": "Florence Nightingale", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b446", "question": "What year did Joseph Merrick, also known as Elephant Man, die?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e04", "question": "What is the Roman name of the Greek god Pan?", "answer": "Faunus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a00e", "question": "Whose Atlantic recordings are collected in a set called \"Queen of Soul\"?", "answer": "Aretha Franklin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ab1861baab681b09292189", "question": "The automotive engineering company, Cosworth, is known for its close relationship with which large car manufacturer?", "answer": "Ford", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abcf", "question": "What country is home to the Bank of Alexandria?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ff", "question": "The Stasi were an intelligence organisation in what country?", "answer": "German Democratic Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db1", "question": "In \"The Fellowship of the Ring\", what does Gandalf do to the ring to make its secret inscription visible?", "answer": "Heat it in the fire", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8f49801dd7bf43be5e824", "question": "Where does Sherry wine come from?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015ff61fe83fe1f2a824c4e", "question": "In 1948, which NBA basketball team did the Harlem Globetrotters defeat which eventually helped break the NBA's color barrier?", "answer": "Minneapolis Lakers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5f0", "question": "Which continent is the home of the tsetse fly?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c2364f032c0db195b47f", "question": "What did ancient Egyptians use as pillows?", "answer": "Wooden or stone headrests", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aba8", "question": "Which US state has Cheyenne as its capital city?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339af6", "question": "What TV science guy wore a red polka-dot bow tie on the box of his \"Way Cool Game of Science\" CD-ROM?", "answer": "Bill Nye", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba51", "question": "What was the denomination of the first American adhesive stamp?", "answer": "Five cents", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e56efe83fe1f2a824bbe", "question": "In which country was Buddha born?", "answer": "Nepal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b97a", "question": "The French Tennis Open is played at which venue?", "answer": "Roland Garros", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0dd", "question": "On what non-Nintendo console can you find \"The Legend of Zelda\" games?", "answer": "Philips CD-i", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff66c8852a821ff76ae8b12", "question": "Which Christian holiday is directly related to the observance of the March equinox?", "answer": "Easter is traditionally celebrated on the Sunday after the first full moon that occurs on or after the March equinox.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2d9", "question": "Arthur Jefferson better known as who?", "answer": "Stan Laurel", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7122a9e54d890926f6db", "question": "Which country claims the island of Saipan as a commonwealth?", "answer": "USA -- Saipan is part of the Northern Mariana Islands, which is a commonwealth of the U.S.  Saipan is the seat of the government.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd96afa23c87fd04dd15e17", "question": "What US president liked to celebrate his birthday by skydiving?", "answer": "George H.W. Bush", "category": "history"}]